fountasandpinnell.com 2019-06-26

# 

                                                PRIVACY POLICY
                                           Effective Date: October 1, 2012
                                                      Overview
You should read this entire Privacy Policy, but here are some high points detailed below:
            We ask you for, and use technology to detect, information about you. Some of this information is
             shared with others.
            You consent to our practices detailed below. If you want to change your consent, terminate your
             account and stop using the Site(s).
            Click here for an index of topics covered below. You may click on any topic to go to the details.
To view our Terms of Use, click here. To request copies of both the Privacy Policy and Terms of Use
documents by email, click here.
                                                    Introduction
Welcome! You have arrived at a site that is owned and/or operated by Heinemann, a division of Greenwood
Publishing Group, Inc. (“Heinemann” or “we,” “our” or “us”). This “Privacy Policy” governs your use of our
Heinemann.com Website available at www.heinemann.com (including, without limitation, both mobile and
online versions of our site), and also applies to your use of interactive features, widgets, applications, content or
downloads that we make available through the Heinemann.com Website and post this Privacy Policy
(collectively, the “Site(s)”) regardless of how you access or use them, whether via personal computers, mobile
devices or otherwise but does not apply to data we receive from third parties unless we combine such data with
Personal Information (defined below) that we have ourselves collected under this Privacy Policy. Our
statements under this Privacy Policy only cover information collected at the Site(s) directly by us, and not by
third parties that may interact with our Site(s).
This Privacy Policy does not apply to our data collection activities offline or otherwise outside of our Site(s)
(unless otherwise stated below). To the extent we provide you notice on our Site(s) of different or additional
privacy policies or practices (e.g., at the point of our collection), those additional terms shall govern such data
collection and use. Due to the diverse nature of our businesses, companies within the Houghton Mifflin family
of companies may have different privacy policies. In such cases, the privacy policy of the particular company
will be posted, and will supersede the terms of this Privacy Policy in the event of a conflict.
In addition, please review the Site(s)’ Terms of Use, which governs your use of the Site(s). By using our
Site(s), you consent to our Privacy Policy and Terms of Use and our collection, use and sharing of your
information and data, and other activities, as described below.
17072891

                                              Linkable Table of Contents
It is important that you read and understand the entire Privacy Policy before using the Site(s). This table
of contents highlights key issues and points. You can click on the headings or the “More” links to be taken
to the full explanation.
1. What Information Do the Site(s) Collect?
           (a) Information You Provide To Us
                You may give us Personal Information and Demographic Information, such as when you register
                or contact us. More
           (b) Information We Collect As You Access and Use the Site(s)
                Tracking Technologies collect Usage Information based on your Device Identifier. More
           (c) Information Third Parties Provide About You
                We may obtain information about you from third parties. More
           (d) Information You Provide About a Third Party
                You may give us information about others, such as when you send a friend a message through the
                Site(s). More
2.     How Do We Use the Information Collected?
                We use your Personal Information, Demographic Information and Usage Information for a variety
                of purposes. More
3.     How and When Do We Disclose Information To Third Parties?
       We may provide your information to third parties under various circumstances. More These may
       include:
           (a) When You Request Information From or Provide Information to Third Parties
                If you request information from third parties, request that we send information to third parties or
                interact with third party sites, content, ads or tools (including Facebook and other third party share
                functionality) we may share your information with such parties and/or they may collect your
                information directly. More
           (b) Third Parties Providing Services on Our Behalf
                Our vendors may collect your information or we may share it with them. This includes third party
                content and course providers and/or operators. More
           (c) Administrative and Legal Reasons
                There are a variety of administrative and legal reasons for which we may share your information.
                More
                                                                                            Page 2 of 12
17072891

          (d) Affiliates and Business Transfer
               We may share your information with our Affiliates or in the event of a sale, merger or similar
               transaction. More
          (e) Co-branded Areas
               Co-branded areas may include information collection by us and third parties. Such third parties’
               privacy policies, not ours, govern their practices. More
           (f) Sweepstakes, Contests and Promotions
               Promotions entrants may be required to consent to certain information sharing. More
          (g) License Managers
               If you use the Site(s) under a multi-user account, the master account holder may have access to
               your information.
4.     What About Information I Disclose Publicly?
          (a) User Generated Content and Public Information
               Posting content in public areas makes it available to others. More
          (b) Name and Likeness
               You grant us the right to use your name and likeness in connection with your posting and
               activities. More
          (c) Profiles
               Learn about your profile settings. More
5.     Do Third Party Content and Links To Third Party Site(s) Appear on the Site(s)?
       We are not responsible for your interaction with third party content or locations. More
6.     Do Third Party Applications Appear on the Site(s)?
       We are not responsible for your interaction with third party applications. More
7.     How Do I Change My Information and Communications Preferences?
       You may change certain account information and preferences. More
8.     What About Transfer of Information To the United States?
       Data may be transferred to the United States. More
9.     What Should Parents Know About Children?
                                                                                          Page 3 of 12
17072891

       We do not intend to collect Personal Information from children. If you think we have, let us know. More
10.    What About Security?
       No data security is absolute, but we take reasonable technical, physical and administrative steps to secure
       data appropriately. More
11.    What About Changes To the Privacy Policy?
       We may change this Privacy Policy as explained here.
12.    Who Can I Contact?
       You can contact us for more information about the manner in which we collect, use, disclose and
       otherwise manage your Personal Information. More
                                         The Full Detailed Privacy Policy
1.       What Information Do the Site(s) Collect?
         (a)      Information You Provide To Us
Personal Information and Demographic Information. On the Site(s), we may ask you to provide us with
certain categories of information such as: (1) personally identifiable information, which is information that
identifies you personally, such as your first and last name, e-mail address, mailing address, username and
password and payment information including credit card number (“Personal Information”); and (2)
demographic information, such as information about your occupation, education level, and grades you work
with if you are a professional educator (“Demographic Information”). We may collect this information
through various forms and in various places on the Site(s), including account registration forms, contact us
forms, or when you otherwise interact with the Site(s). If we combine Demographic Information with the
Personal Information we collect directly from you on the Site(s), we will treat the combined data as Personal
Information under this Privacy Policy.
         (b)      Information We Collect or Store As You Access and Use the Site(s)
In addition to any Personal Information or other information that you choose to submit to us via our Site(s), we
and our third-party service providers may use a variety of technologies that automatically (or passively) store or
collect certain information whenever you visit or interact with the Site(s) (“Usage Information”). This Usage
Information may be stored or accessed using a variety of technologies that may be downloaded to your personal
computer, laptop, tablet or mobile phone (a “Device”) whenever you visit or interact with our Site(s). Usage
Information may be non-identifying or may be associated with you. Whenever we associate Usage Information
with your Personal Information, we will treat it as Personal Information.
This Usage Information may include:
            your IP address or other unique identifier (“Device Identifier”). A Device Identifier is a number
             that is automatically assigned to your Device used to access the Site(s), and our computers identify
             your Device by its Device Identifier;
            your Device functionality (including browser, operating system, hardware, mobile network
             information);
            the URL that referred you to our Site(s);
                                                                                         Page 4 of 12
17072891

             the areas within our Site(s) that you visit and your activities there, including remembering you and
              your preferences;
             your Device location;
             your Device characteristics; and
             certain other Device data, including the time of day, among other information.
We may use various developed methods and technologies to store or collect Usage Information (“Tracking
Technologies”). Tracking Technologies may set, change, alter or modify settings or configurations on your
Device. A few of the Tracking Technologies include, without limitation, the following (and subsequent
technology and methods later developed):
Cookies. A cookie is a data file placed on a Device when it is used to visit the Site(s). A Flash cookie (or
locally shared object) is a data file placed on a Device via the Adobe Flash plug-in that may be built-in to or
downloaded by you to your Device. HTML5 cookies can be programmed through HTML5 local storage. Unlike
Flash cookies, HTML5 cookies do not require a plug-in. Regular cookies may generally be disabled or removed
by tools that are available as part of most commercial browsers, and in some but not all instances can be blocked
in the future by selecting certain settings. Each browser you use will need to be set separately and different
browsers offer different functionality and options in this regard. Also, these tools may not be effective with
regard to Flash cookies or HTML5 cookies. For information on disabling Flash cookies go to Adobe’s website
www.adobe.com. Please be aware that if you disable or remove cookies, Flash cookies, or HTML5 cookies on
your Device, some parts of our Site(s) may not function properly, and that when you revisit our Site(s) your
ability to limit cookies is subject to your browser settings and limitations.
Web Beacons. Small graphic images or other web programming code called web beacons (also known as “1x1
GIFs” or “clear GIFs”) may be included in our Site(s)’ pages and messages. Web beacons may be invisible to
you, but any electronic image or other web programming code inserted into a page or e-mail can act as a web
beacon. Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including, without
limitation, to count visitors to the Site(s), to monitor how users navigate the Site(s), to count how many e-mails
that were sent were actually opened or to count how many particular articles or links were actually viewed.
Embedded Scripts. An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your
interactions with the Site(s), such as the links you click on. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your
Device from our web server or a third party service provider, is active only while you are connected to the
Site(s), and is deactivated or deleted thereafter.
ETag, or entity tag. A feature of the cache in browsers. It is an opaque identifier assigned by a web server to a
specific version of a resource found at a URL. If the resource content at that URL ever changes, a new and
different ETag is assigned. Used in this manner ETags are a form of Device Identifier. ETag tracking may
generate unique tracking values even where the consumer blocks HTTP, Flash, and/or HTML5 cookies.
We may use Tracking Technologies for a variety of purposes, including:
Strictly Necessary. We may use cookies or other Tracking Technologies that we consider are strictly necessary
to allow you to use and access our Site(s), including cookies required to prevent fraudulent activity, improve
security or allow you to make use of shopping-cart functionality.
Performance-Related. We may use cookies or other Tracking Technologies that are useful in order to assess
the performance of the Site(s), including as part of our analytic practices or otherwise to improve the content,
products or services offered through the Site(s).
                                                                                            Page 5 of 12
17072891

Functionality-Related. We may use cookies or other Tracking Technologies that are required to offer you
enhanced functionality when accessing the Site(s), including identifying you when you sign-in to our Site(s) or
keeping track of our specified preferences, including in terms of the presentation of content on our Site(s).
Targeting-Related. We may use Tracking Technologies to deliver content and ads relevant to your interests on
our Site(s) based on how you interact with our content. This includes using Tracking Technologies to
understand the usefulness to you of the content that has been delivered to you.
There may be other Tracking Technologies now and later devised and used by us in connection with the Site(s).
Further, third parties may use Tracking Technologies with our Site(s). We may not control those Tracking
Technologies and we are not responsible for them. However, you consent to potentially encountering third party
Tracking Technologies in connection with use of our Site(s) and accept that our statements under this Privacy
Policy do not apply to the Tracking Technologies or practices of such third parties.
          (c)     Information Third Parties Provide About You
We may receive information about you from your friends, colleagues and others that use the Site(s), such as
when they submit content to us or post on the Site(s). Additionally, we may, from time to time, supplement the
information we collect directly from you on our Site(s) with outside records from third parties for various
purposes, including to enhance our ability to serve you, to tailor our content to you and to offer you
opportunities that may be of interest to you. To the extent we combine information we receive from those
sources with Personal Information we collect on the Site(s), it will be treated as Personal Information and we
will apply this Privacy Policy to such combined information, unless we have disclosed otherwise. In no other
circumstances do our promises under this Privacy Policy apply to information we receive about you from third
parties.
          (d)     Information You Provide About a Third Party
You may send someone else a communication from the Site(s), such as sending an invitation to a friend or
family member. Please ensure that you only send such communications to friends and family once you have
their permission. If so, the information you provide (e.g., names, e-mail addresses, mobile number, etc.) is used
to facilitate the communication and is not used by us for any other marketing purpose unless we obtain consent
from that person or we explicitly say otherwise. Please be aware that when you use any send-to-a-friend
functionality on our Site(s), your e-mail address, mobile number, name or user name and message may be
included in the communication sent to your addressee(s). Some of these tools may be third party tools subject to
third party privacy policies as further detailed in Section 5 and Section 6.
2.        How Do We Use the Information Collected?
We may use your Personal Information, Demographic Information or Usage Information that is subject to this
Privacy Policy: (1) to provide you with information or services or process transactions that you have requested
or agreed to receive including to send you electronic newsletters, or to provide you with special offers or
promotional materials on behalf of us or third parties; (2) to enable you to participate in a variety of the Site(s)’
features such as online lectures, courses and or other educational opportunities; (3) to process your registration
with the Site(s), including verifying your information is active and valid; (4) to improve the Site(s) or our
services, to customize your experience on the Site(s), or to serve you specific content that is relevant to you; (5)
to contact you with regard to your use of the Site(s) and, in our discretion, changes to the Site(s) and/or Site(s)’
policies; (6) for internal business purposes such as troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research and service
improvement; and (7) for purposes disclosed at the time you provide your information or as otherwise set forth
in this Privacy Policy.
                                                                                          Page 6 of 12
17072891

Please note that information submitted to the Site(s) via a “contact us” or other similar function may not receive
a response; we will not use that information so provided to contact you for marketing purposes unrelated to your
inquiry unless you agree otherwise.
3.       How and When Do We Disclose Information to Third Parties?
We may share non-Personal Information, such as aggregated user statistics, with third parties. We may share
your Device Identifiers with third parties along with data related to you and your activities. We do not share
your Personal Information with third parties for those third parties’ marketing purposes unless you consent to
such sharing at the time you provide your Personal Information. In addition, we may share the information we
have collected about you, including Personal Information, as disclosed at the time you provide your information
and as described below or otherwise in this Privacy Policy.
         (a)      When You Request Information From or Provide Information to Third Parties. You may
be presented with an option on our Site(s) to receive certain information and/or marketing offers directly from
third parties or to have us send certain information to third parties or give them access to it. If you choose to do
so, your Personal Information and other information may be disclosed to such third parties and all information
you disclose will be subject to the third party privacy policies and practices of such third parties. As examples,
we may offer you the opportunity to provide information on your completion of courses or activities to your
employer, certification organizations and/or third party institutions that offer academic and/or continuing
education credit. If you exercise such an option you consent to our providing all information requested by them.
In addition, third parties may store, collect or otherwise have access to your information when you interact with
their Tracking Technologies, tools, content or apps on our Site(s) or link to them from our Site(s). This may
include using third party tools such as Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest or other third party posting or content
sharing tools. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and practices of such third parties and, therefore,
you should review such third party privacy policies and practices of such third parties prior to requesting
information from or otherwise interacting with them.
         (b)      Third Parties Providing Services on Our Behalf. We may use third party vendors to perform
certain services on behalf of us or the Site(s), such as hosting the Site(s), designing and/or operating the Site(s)’
features, tracking the Site(s)’ activities and analytics, and enabling us to send you special offers or perform other
administrative services. This may include content or courses provided or operated by, in whole or in part, third
parties, but we require them not to use your Personal Information for their own purposes without your express
consent. We may provide these vendors with access to user information, including Device Identifiers and
Personal Information, to carry out the services they are performing for you or for us. If you request that we
share information with third parties (e.g., your employer or a certification organization), such authorization also
applies to our third party content/course providers. Third party analytics service providers may set and access
their own Tracking Technologies on your Device and they may otherwise collect or have access to your
Personal Information. We are not responsible for those third party technologies or activities arising out of them.
However, some may offer you certain choices regarding their practices, and information we have been informed
of regarding such choices is available here.
         (c)      Administrative and Legal Reasons. We may access, use, preserve, transfer and disclose your
information (including Device Identifiers and Personal Information), including disclosure to third parties: (i) to
satisfy any applicable law, regulation, subpoenas, governmental requests or legal process if in our good faith
opinion such is required or permitted by law; (ii) to protect and/or defend the Site(s)’ Terms of Use or other
policies applicable to the Site(s), including investigation of potential violations thereof; (iii) to protect the safety,
rights, property or security of the Site(s) or any third party; and/or (iv) to detect, prevent or otherwise address
fraud, security or technical issues. Further, we may use IP address or other Device Identifiers, to identify users,
and may do so in cooperation with third parties such as copyright owners, internet service providers, wireless
service providers and/or law enforcement agencies, including disclosing such information to third parties, all in
our discretion, subject to applicable law. Such disclosures may be carried out without notice to you.
                                                                                             Page 7 of 12
17072891

          (d)      Affiliates and Business Transfer. We may share your information, including your Device
Identifiers and Personal Information, Demographic Information and Usage Information with our parent,
subsidiaries and affiliates (“Affiliates”). We also reserve the right to disclose and transfer all such information:
(i) to a subsequent owner, co-owner or operator of the Site(s) or applicable database; or (ii) in connection with a
merger, consolidation, restructuring, the sale of substantially all of our interests and/or assets or other corporate
change, including, during the course of any due diligence process.
          (e)      Co-branded Areas. Certain areas of the Site(s) may be provided to you in association with
third parties (“Co-Branded Areas”) such as sponsors, schools and educational organizations and may require
you to disclose Personal Information to them. Such Co-Branded Areas will identify the third party and indicate
if they have a privacy policy that applies to their collection and use of you information. If you elect to register
for products and/or services, communicate with such third parties or download their content or applications, at
Co-Branded Areas, you may be providing your information to both us and the third party. Further, if you sign-
in to a Co-Branded Area with a username and password obtained on the Site(s), your Personal Information may
be disclosed to the identified third parties for that Co-Branded Area. We are not responsible for such third
party’s data collection or practices and you should look to such third party privacy policies for more
information.
          (f)      Sweepstakes, Contests and Promotions. We may offer sweepstakes, contests, and other
promotions (any, a “Promotion”) through the Site(s) that may require registration. By participating in a
Promotion, you are agreeing to official rules that govern that Promotion, which may contain specific
requirements of you, including, allowing the sponsor of the Promotion to use your name, voice and/or likeness
in advertising or marketing associated with the Promotion. If you choose to enter a Promotion, Personal
Information may be disclosed to third parties or the public in connection with the administration of such
Promotion, including, in connection with winner selection, prize fulfillment, and as required by law or permitted
by the Promotion’s official rules, such as on a winners list.
          (g)      License Managers. If you are using the Site(s), as a designated user under a multi-user
account, such as if you are a teacher using the Site(s) under your school’s or school district’s account, your
Site(s) activities and related information, including, without limitation, completion rates, number and time of
logins, length of time spent, and performance measurements, may be available to the master account holder, and
in particular its license manager.
4.        What About Information I Disclose Publicly?
          (a)      User Generated Content and Public Information. When you register with the Site(s), you
may create your own profile. Your profile information, as well as your name, e-mail, photo, and other
information you provide are displayed in the places specified in your profile to enable you to connect with
people on the Site(s). As part of the interactive aspects of the Site(s), some Personal Information of registered
users of the Site(s) (“Members”) and postings may be automatically displayed to the public on the Site(s) as
part of a Member’s profile page (refer to Section 4(c) below). Additionally, the Site(s) permit you to submit
and/or publicly post ideas, photographs, lessons, lectures, writings, music, video, audio recordings, computer
graphics, pictures, data, questions, comments, suggestions or other content, including Personal Information
(collectively, “User Content”), such as on your profile page, blogs and message boards. We or others may
store, display, reproduce, publish, distribute or otherwise use User Content online or offline in any media or
format (currently existing or hereafter developed) and may or may not attribute it to you. Others may have
access to this User Content and may have the ability to share it with third parties. Postings to chat rooms,
message boards, other Member’s profiles, bulletin boards, or similar public forums where you and other users of
our Site(s) can communicate are public or semi-public, and therefore may be reviewed by Members and non-
Members, indexed by third-party search engines and appear in search results on third-party websites.
Accordingly, you should exercise discretion and good judgment regarding what you elect to include as User
Content. Please note that Heinemann does not control who will have access to the information that you choose
to make public, and cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will
                                                                                            Page 8 of 12
17072891

respect your privacy or keep it secure. Our promises under this Privacy Policy do not apply to any information
that you disclose publicly, share with others or otherwise upload onto the publicly available positions of our
Site(s). We are not responsible for the accuracy, use or misuse of any User Content that you disclose or receive
from third parties through the Site(s).
         (b)     Name and Likeness. We may also publish your name, voice, likeness and other Personal
Information that is part of your User Content, and we may use the content, or any portion of the content, for
advertising, marketing, publicity and promotional activities. For full terms and conditions regarding User
Content you submit to the Site(s), please review our Terms of Use.
         (c)     Profiles. A Member’s profile page may be, by default, set up to display information such as the
Member’s display name, images, location (city/state/country), groups that the Member has joined and optional
information added by the Member including, for example, the Member’s tagline, photographs and educational
materials, etc. We may make it possible for Members to see a report on other Members that visited a profile
page and this gives Members access to such visitor’s profile pages. Profile information is used by us primarily
to be presented back to and edited by you when you access the Site(s) and to be presented to others permitted to
view that information on the Site(s). In some cases (e.g., posting to your page), other users of the Site(s) may be
able to supplement your profile. We may offer Members the ability to manage their public profile and use
profile preference settings on the Edit Profile page, the functionality and features of which are subject to change
from time-to-time so visit it frequently to confirm the settings reflect your then current preferences and we
recommend that you do not post information or content as part of your profile that you are not prepared to make
public. Changing setting options may not result in immediate changes to the settings, which are subject to our
operations and maintenance schedules. Members should carefully consider the use of such settings to improve
information display options and to ensure the settings are properly set and functioning in the manner desired.
Notwithstanding the availability of profile preference settings, you should be aware that these settings are for
convenience only, do not employ complex data security protection and may not be error free. Further, other
users that have access may repost or otherwise make public your information or content. Accordingly,
discretion and good judgment should be exercised when posting information or content as part of your profile.
5.       Do Third Party Content and Links to Third Party Site(s) Appear on the Site(s)?
The Site(s) may contain content that is supplied by a third party, and those third parties may collect Usage
Information and your Device Identifier when pages from the Site(s) are served to you. In addition, when you
are on the Site(s) you may be directed to other sites that are operated and controlled by third parties that we do
not control. We are not responsible for the data collection and privacy practices employed by any of these third
parties or their sites. For example, if you “click” on a link, the “click” may take you off the Site(s) onto a
different site. These other sites may associate their Tracking Technologies with you, independently collect data
about you, including Personal Information, and may or may not have their own published privacy policies. We
encourage you to note when you leave our Site(s) and to review the third party privacy policies of all third party
locations and exercise caution in connection with them.
6.       Do Third Party Applications Appear on the Site(s)?
Third party applications may be available via the Site(s). The owners of these applications (“Third Party
Owners”) may collect Personal Information and other data from you and may have their own policies and
practices. We are not responsible for how Third Party Owners or their applications collect or use your
information. These Third Party Owners may have their own terms of service, privacy policies or other policies
and ask you to agree to the same. We are not responsible for these third party privacy policies or the practices
of Third Party Owners. Be sure to review any available policies before submitting any personally identifiable
information to a third party application or otherwise interacting with it and exercise caution in connection with
these applications.
                                                                                          Page 9 of 12
17072891

7.       How Do I Change My Information and Communications Preferences?
You are responsible for maintaining the accuracy of the information you submit to us, such as your contact
information provided as part of registration. The Site(s) may allow you to review, correct or update Personal
Information you have provided through the Site(s)’ registration forms or otherwise, and you may provide
registration updates and changes, and otherwise request access to your information, by contacting us at
custserv@heinemann.com. If so, we will make good faith efforts to make requested changes in our then active
databases as soon as reasonably practicable. Please note that it is not always possible to completely remove or
delete all of your information from our databases and that residual data may remain on backup media or for
other reasons. Also, if you have made any public postings on the Site(s) such as in forums or blogs, these
communications cannot generally be removed. When you edit your Personal Information or change your
preferences on the Site(s), information that you remove may persist internally for Heinemann’s administrative
purposes. You may cancel or modify our e-mail marketing communications you receive from us by following
the instructions contained within our promotional e-mails or in some cases by logging into your account and
changing your communication preferences. This will not affect subsequent subscriptions and if your opt-out is
limited to certain types of e-mails the opt-out will be so limited. Please note that we reserve the right to send
you certain communications relating to your account or use of our Site(s), such as administrative and service
announcements and these transactional account messages may be unaffected if you choose to opt-out from
receiving our marketing communications. If you have any questions about the Privacy Policy or practices
described in it, you should contact us by e-mail at: custserv@heinemann.com.
8.       What About Transfer of Information To the United States?
Our Site(s) are operated in the United States and intended for users located in the United States and Canada. If
you are located outside of the United States, please be aware that information we collect, including Personal
Information, will be transferred to, and processed, stored and used in the United States. The data protection
laws in the United States may differ from those of the country in which you are located, and your Personal
Information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in the United
States according to laws of the United States. By using the Site(s) or providing us with any information, you
consent to the transfer to, and processing, usage, sharing and storage of your information, including Personal
Information, in the United States as set forth in this Privacy Policy.
9.       What Should Parents Know About Children?
The Site(s) are general audience web sites and we do not knowingly collect any personal information from
children younger than the age of thirteen (13) as required by U.S. law. We will delete any personal information
collected that we later determine to be from a user younger than the age of thirteen (13). If you are a parent or
guardian of a child under the age of thirteen (13) and believe he or she has disclosed personal information to us,
please contact us at custserv@heinemann.com.
10.      What About Security?
We incorporate commercially reasonable technical, physical and administrative safeguards to help protect and
secure your Personal Information in our custody or control. However, no data transmission over the Internet,
mobile networks, wireless transmission or electronic storage of information can be guaranteed to be 100%
secure. Please note that we cannot ensure the security of any information you transmit to us, and you use our
Site(s) and provide us with your information at your own risk.
11.      What About Changes To the Privacy Policy?
We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time without notice to you. Any changes will be
effective immediately upon the posting of the revised Privacy Policy. We will not use your Personal
Information, however, in a manner materially different than promised at the time it was collected without your
                                                                                        Page 10 of 12
17072891

consent. To the extent any provision of this Privacy Policy is found by a competent tribunal to be invalid or
unenforceable, such provision shall be severed to the extent necessary for the remainder to be valid and
enforceable.
12.      Who can I Contact?
If you have questions, comments or complaints regarding our Privacy Policy or the manner in which we or our
service providers treat your Personal Information, contact us at custserv@heinemann.com.
                                                                                     Page 11 of 12
17072891

Third Party Information
The following third parties that collect information from you on our Site(s) have given us notice that you may
obtain information on their policies and practices, and in some instances opt-out of certain of their activities, as
follows:
        Party               Service          For More Information      Use of Tracking       Privacy Choices
                                                                         Technologies
    Adobe           Online Marketing         Adobe hosted services            Yes           See information
                    Services, On Demand                                                     links in prior
                    Services and/or other    Other Adobe privacy                            column
                    Adobe-hosted             policies
                    services
    Google          Google Analytics for     Google Analytics for             Yes           See information
                    Display Advertisers,     display advertisers                            links in prior
                    Ads Preferences          policy                                         column
                    Manager, and Google
                    Analytics Opt-out        Google ads preferences
                    Browser Add-on
                                             Google Analytics opt-
                                             out browser add-on
 NOTE: We are not responsible for third party policies or practices. We try to keep this information current,
  but it is provided as a courtesy and may not be current or accurate. Please contact the applicable third parties
  regarding their privacy and data security policies and practices.
                                                                                       Page 12 of 12
17072891
